How much is a reasonable amount of
testosterone to take a week for a
beginner? I guess as TRT.
>> Oh, as TRT. Yeah. Um, it just depends.
Like I said, I start people um my
general starting point is really around
80 milligrams twice a week for test sip.
Um, if I start them on cream, I start
everybody at two clicks a day in the
morning only just to assess how their
body absorbs the cream after three or
four weeks. I want to make sure they
absorb it. see where those two clicks
put them as an individual. After that,
it's off to the races with them trying,
you know, where they want to be, if they
want to do twice a day or not. If their
levels are at 2500 on two clicks, I
might be like, "Hey, try one click now."
Oh, hey, let's reduce the concentration,
you know, or if their levels are 600 on
two clicks, we might be like, "Cream may
not be for you." I mean, we'll still try
it, but you know, there's a happy medium
of absorption, but it gets cost
prohibitive if you're one of those poor
absorbers. But um yeah, it's going to
totally depend on your provider. I know
providers that start people on the low
end. I think 100 milligrams a week total
is probably as low as one should be
started and even then that's pretty darn
low for most people. If you start them
with frequent injections, it probably
will be okay. Like if you did a daily or
every other day, but most beginners
aren't going to do that. Um I I just
feel like a starting point of yeah 140
to 160 140 to you know somewhere in
there total weekly is a good starting
point. Right. And then but it's always
about the individual and how they
respond to it and then adjusting based
on how they feel.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. For cream it also depends uh the
the base in which the testosterone is uh
compounded. I already shared it in
another video but I've used for six
years I guess uh two times three clicks
a day 20% in a liposomaal base just to
get levels of 1200 nanograms per dill
total testosterone. Then last year I
switched to HRTbase and for the to to
reach the same levels I can get away
with two times two clicks.
>> Nice.
>> Y
less cream it's uh cheaper for me.
>> Exactly. Yeah. That's still the same.
>> Exactly. And that's my I want to help
people with the cost part of it too. So
I'm always like I start everybody with a
Trievis base because that's easy to get
here. I think it's a little edge above
HRT as far as it's but they're very
similar and I I had good result. I
started with HRT base. I like a Trievis
as far as the um consistency of it, the
way it dries a little better, but
otherwise it's pretty equivalent as far
as um absorption and levels. The
liposomaal, yeah, I have not seen I I
feel and I can't remember I have talked
to my wife about it. Liposal tends to be
better for females to the vaginal
mucosa. I think it's specifically best
for that area and when guys try to use
it on scrotal or even regular skin, it's
just not going to absorb the same way. I
have to confirm that. But I think that's
the deal with liposomaal.
>> Yeah. Well, I get the same absorption
from four clicks total instead of six
clicks on the liposomaal base.
>> Nice. Yeah.